bombayduck.co.uk 2008-12-18

# bombayduck

Privacy and Data Protection   
  
## Security of your Information

We realise how important it is to securely store all information that you provide to us, so we treat any information you provide us with great care and we maintain the highest level of security. 

By visiting the Bombay Duck website you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in our privacy policy.  Your use of this website signifies your consent to the collection, processing and use of personal information by Bombay Duck for the purposes of processing your order, processing your payment, market research, fraud detection and for marketing purposes as described below.  Any changes to our privacy policy will be posted on this site so that you can ensure you are fully informed of your rights and can notify us of any changes to your preferences. 

All personal information (including payment card details) is encrypted to maintain your privacy using high level SSL encryption technology, the most advanced security software currently available for online transactions.  We also follow a tight security procedure as required under UK Data Protection Legislation (the Data Protection Act 1998) to protect the information we store about you from unauthorised access. 

## Information we Collect and Why

When you place an order, request a catalogue, sign up to our email newsletter or otherwise interact with the Bombay Duck website we may require certain information and you may submit personal information to us as follows: 

  1. When you register with Bombay Duck we ask for information such as your name, address, delivery address, telephone number, email address, contact details and if you place an order your credit card details.  We keep a record of this information. We need this information to process your requests and recognize you as a registered customer.
  2. We keep a record of any emails or other messages you may send us.  This helps us provide customer support services to you.
  3. We keep a record of the orders you have placed with Bombay Duck so we can provide you with an efficient, reliable service and deal with any problems quickly.  It also means we can send you the most relevant Bombay Duck offers.
  4. We may monitor, record and play back telephone calls for training new staff and to improve the quality of our customer service.
  5. We may receive information about you from third parties and add this to our account information.  For example we update address information using the Royal Mail Change of Address file which we may use to change our records and deliver your catalogues. 

## How we use the Information we Collect

The information we keep is used to improve the service we offer you.  We may use the information to: 

  1. Open and run your Bombay Duck customer account
  2. Process and deliver your Bombay Duck order
  3. Provide customer service to you 
  4. Research
  5. Provide you with information about the products and services we offer
  6. Help prevent fraud (we may check your credit rating with credit agencies such as Equifax. We may check credit card details with our credit agency and reserve the right to refuse orders on this basis. At all times where we disclose your information it will remain secure).
  7. Send you offers from other companies but only with your permission.
  8. We may need to pass your contact information to our couriers in case they need to contact you to arrange the delivery of your order.

## Bombay Duck Marketing Communications

When you register with Bombay Duck you will be given the option to receive fabulous promotional emails from Bombay Duck.    If you would like to receive these emails please select the tick box on the registration page.  If you do not tick this box you will not receive these promotional emails.  You can unsubscribe from these promotional emails at any time by using the unsubscribe link provided in every email, sending an email to [unsubscribe@bombayduck.com](mailto:unsubscribe@bombayduck.com) **(link to unsubscribe email)** or writing to us and we will remove your email address from our marketing records. You can also change your marketing preferences by logging into the ‘My Account’ section of the website. 

We may also send you the Bombay Duck catalogue by post to your registered account address.  If you do not want to receive Bombay Duck catalogues please send an email to _[unsubscribecatalogue@bombayduck.com](mailto:unsubscribecatalogue@bombayduck.com)_ **(link to unsubscribe from catalogue email)** or write to us to let us know. 

Bombay Duck will not pass your information on to any third parties unless you consent to this.  When you register with Bombay Duck you will be given the option to receive information and offers by post from carefully selected and reputable third parties that we genuinely think may interest you.  If you would like to receive these promotions from third parties by post please select the tick box on the registration page.  If you do not tick this box you will not receive these promotions from third parties.  If you no longer wish to receive information from third parties please notify us by emailing _[optout@bombayduck.com](mailto:optout@bombayduck.com)_ **(link to unsubscribe from third party mailings email)** or by writing to us.  You can also change your preferences by logging into the ‘My Account’ section of the website. We will _never_ pass your email address to a third party. 

We track visits made to our website so we can see which products and pages are the most popular.  This allows us to improve our product selection and website to make shopping at Bombay Duck even better. This tracking is anonymous, we do not know your personal details. 

## Cookies

We obtain some information automatically using ‘cookies’ when you use our website.  Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer when you visit certain web pages.  Bombay Duck uses cookies to remember you when you come to our site and to keep track of what you have in your basket.  Cookies make the interaction between users and websites faster and easier. Cookies cannot harm your computer and do not contain any private or personal information. 

You can set your website to reject cookies by adjusting your internet browser settings not to accept cookies. The help option on your web browser should explain how to do this or you can go to <http://www.aboutcookies.org/> for more details about cookies and how to reject them. However please be aware that the Bombay Duck website (like most shopping websites) will not work without cookies. 

## Removal of Information

You have the right to remove your personal information and change your preferences at any time. In order to do this please email us at [amelie@bombayduck.com](mailto:amelie@bombayduck.com) **(link to email with subject ‘Removal of Information’)** or write to us at: 

The Data Protection Officer  
Bombay Duck   
231 The Vale   
London   
W3 7QS UK 

Please include your name, address, account number and/or the e-mail address you registered with when you contact us. 

## Further Information

If you have any questions or you are unsure about the personal account information we are holding in your name please contact us.  We will happily review your file and update your records if you require. You can also check the account information we are holding online by logging into your account and going to ‘My Details’.
